Sioned Mai Snowden

Address 24 Strongs Close, Sherston Malmesbury SN16 0NU

Email

sionedsnowden@gmail.com

Tel 07772 067872

Profile

Determined, hard-working and attentive **BSc Zoology** graduate driven by a passion for providing the best possible care and support for both animals and their owners. Organised and confident with the capacity to integrate well within teams of varying size and complexity, now seeking to build upon previous work experience within the field of animal science.

Key Skills & Experience

Self Management & Initiative

Experience of working within roles requiring **strong initiative** and self-management skills. Examples include **sole responsibility** for the administration of the Wiltshire Mammal Group and the day-to-day running of a popular boutique children's shoe shop.

Academic Performance

Graduated with a **BSc Hons 2:1 degree in Zoology** from Aberystwyth University (**IBERS**) in Summer 2015. This four-year degree included one year of **industry-related work experience** undertaken with the Wiltshire and Swindon Biological Records Centre.

Targetted Communication

Substantial previous exposure to the general public requiring varied styles of written and verbal communication appropriate to the target audience. Key examples include close interaction with young children and vulnerable adults whilst working as a Shoe Fitter and Health Care Assistant respectively, in addition to conducting meetings and producing administrative documentation whilst volunteering at the WSBRC.

Team Integration & Collaboration

Experience of integrating within a range of working team environments, beginning from the sole daytime running of a busy shoe shop, to moving into a close-knit office-based team, before most recently working as part of substantially-sized nursing team within a busy hospital setting.

Work Experience

April 2011 to Present

Shoe Fitter & Sales Assistant

Apples and Pairs Children's Shoes - Sherston, Wiltshire

- Responsible for sole charge of the shop as part of day-to-day activities.
- Awarded responsibility and trust to undertake managerial activities including shop opening and cashing up at end of day.
- Developed team and leadership skills following promotion to supervisor and staff trainer.
- Gained full accreditation as a Start-Rite shoe fitter, ensuring the ability to provide the best possible service for customers
- Experience of working closely with stock control and eCommerce systems through processing internet orders from Amazon.co.uk and via the company's own website.

June 2014 to Sept 2014

Health Care Assistant (Bank)

NHS Gloucestershire

- Responsible for the basic care of hospital patients including washing, feeding, dressing and ensuring the overall comfort of vulnerable individuals.
- Received valuable insight and experience in having to work fluidly within a large team often within a high pressure and fast-paced environment.
- Role required the ability to quickly adapt and change task depending upon the current situation. This at times
 would involve having to react efficiently to a rapidly changing situation (e.g. decline in patient health or in
 response to direction from nursing staff).
- Gained a clear understanding of how to communicate appropriately with vulnerable individuals (most commonly elderly patients suffering from dementia), and how important appropriate levels of reassurance and compassion can be in providing high quality patient care.

Attended the basic patient moving and handling course providing details of how to correctly transfer individuals incapable of independent movement.

July 2013 to

Conservation Volunteer

May 2014

Wiltshire Mammal Group (WWT) - Devises, Wiltshire

- · Undertook the general organisation and administration of the Wiltshire Mammal Group. This role included planning and attendance of meetings, booking and organising of events, production of both internal and external documentation (e.g. meeting minutes and newsletters) and the processing of animal record data for the
- · Worked closely with conservation specialists to deploy Dormouse tubes in order to obtain data regarding the current state of the Dormouse population along Wiltshire canals.

Oct 2012 to

Volunteer

April 2013

Magic of Life Butterfly House - Rheidol, Ceredigion

- · Primarily responsible for the feeding, cleaning and general care of the different insect and fish species on display at the centre. This included the maintenance of insect habitats, and in particular of the flora within the butterfly house.
- Awarded sole responsibility for performing tests on habitats to ensure correct conditions were maintained for different species. In particular, these included salinity and nitrogen tests within marine water tanks.
- Continued to build up confidence and communication ability as a result of discussing and explaining biological concepts and insect characteristics to the visitors of the centre.

Education

Sept 2011 to

BSc (Hons) Zoology with Industrial Year

June 2015

Aberystwyth University, Aberystwyth

- Graduated Summer 2015 with a final grade of Second Class, Division 1.
- Dissertation: "Investigating the impacts of climate change on UK butterfly populations" (awarded 2:1).
- Detailed breakdown of all module grades available on request.

Sept 2004 to

June 2011

Westonbirt Girls School, Gloucestershire

- A-Levels: ICT (B), Geography (B), Biology (C)
- 8 GCSEs A*-B including: English Literature and Language (B, B), Double Sciences (A, A) and Maths (B)

Volunteering

Current

Basic First Aider (In Training)

Dec 2014

St John Cymru-Wales, Aberystwyth Division

Currently training as a St John Ambulance Basic First Aider via Aberystwyth University First Aid society (LINKS). Actively involved in duties within Aberystwyth and the surrounding area in non-medical roles at this present time, with the aim of beginning medical roles once training is complete.

Interests and Activities

Besides assisting in caring for the family's two horses, I have a real passion for baking and cookery. I also enjoy staying active through running and swimming, and am currently in training for my first 10km race at the end of this year.

Referees

Ms. Purgle Linham

Records Centre Manager

Wiltshire and Swindon Biological Records Centre c.o. WWT Elm Tree Court Long Street, Devises, Wiltshire, SN10 1NJ

Tel: +44 (0)1380 736072

Email: purglel@wiltshirewildlife.org

Mr. David Powell

Lecturer & Dissertation Supervisor

Institute of Biological, Environmental and Rural Sciences Room 0.24, New IBERS Building, Aberystwyth University Aberystwyth, Ceredigion, SY23 3FL

Tel: +44 (0)1970 621620 Email: dip@aber.ac.uk